export const questions = {
  easy: [
    {
      question: "What is the symbol of Hydrogen?",
      options: ["H", "He", "Hy", "Hg"],
      answer: "H",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the atomic number 2?",
      options: ["Helium", "Hydrogen", "Lithium", "Oxygen"],
      answer: "Helium",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the symbol of Oxygen?",
      options: ["Ox", "O", "Og", "On"],
      answer: "O",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element’s symbol is 'Na'?",
      options: ["Nitrogen", "Neon", "Sodium", "Nickel"],
      answer: "Sodium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the atomic number 1?",
      options: ["Hydrogen", "Helium", "Lithium", "Carbon"],
      answer: "Hydrogen",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is represented by 'C'?",
      options: ["Calcium", "Carbon", "Chlorine", "Copper"],
      answer: "Carbon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Fe'?",
      options: ["Francium", "Iron", "Fluorine", "Fermium"],
      answer: "Iron",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the symbol of Gold?",
      options: ["G", "Go", "Au", "Ag"],
      answer: "Au",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the lightest element in the periodic table?",
      options: ["Helium", "Hydrogen", "Neon", "Lithium"],
      answer: "Hydrogen",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'O'?",
      options: ["Osmium", "Oxygen", "Oxide", "Oganesson"],
      answer: "Oxygen",
    },
  ],

  medium: [
    {
      question: "Which element is a halogen?",
      options: ["Bromine", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Bromine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which group are the Alkali metals in?",
      options: ["Group 1", "Group 2", "Group 17", "Group 18"],
      answer: "Group 1",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic number of Neon?",
      options: ["8", "9", "10", "11"],
      answer: "10",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is a noble gas?",
      options: ["Argon", "Nitrogen", "Oxygen", "Chlorine"],
      answer: "Argon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is a metal?",
      options: ["Iron", "Carbon", "Oxygen", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Iron",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is a transition metal?",
      options: ["Copper", "Calcium", "Carbon", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Copper",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is liquid at room temperature?",
      options: ["Mercury", "Bromine", "Both A and B", "Gallium"],
      answer: "Both A and B",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element’s symbol is 'K'?",
      options: ["Krypton", "Potassium", "Kalium", "Kadmium"],
      answer: "Potassium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Ag'?",
      options: ["Gold", "Silver", "Argon", "Sodium"],
      answer: "Silver",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is known as quicksilver?",
      options: ["Silver", "Mercury", "Lead", "Platinum"],
      answer: "Mercury",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic number of Carbon?",
      options: ["4", "6", "8", "12"],
      answer: "6",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Zn'?",
      options: ["Zinc", "Zirconium", "Zircon", "Zyklon"],
      answer: "Zinc",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element’s symbol is 'N'?",
      options: ["Neon", "Nitrogen", "Nickel", "Niobium"],
      answer: "Nitrogen",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the most abundant element in Earth's atmosphere?",
      options: ["Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Carbon Dioxide", "Argon"],
      answer: "Nitrogen",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the atomic number 26?",
      options: ["Nickel", "Iron", "Cobalt", "Manganese"],
      answer: "Iron",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest atomic number?",
      options: ["Uranium", "Oganesson", "Francium", "Radon"],
      answer: "Oganesson",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Pb'?",
      options: ["Phosphorus", "Palladium", "Lead", "Platinum"],
      answer: "Lead",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is used in light bulb filaments?",
      options: ["Iron", "Tungsten", "Copper", "Zinc"],
      answer: "Tungsten",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an alkali metal?",
      options: ["Potassium", "Calcium", "Barium", "Magnesium"],
      answer: "Potassium",
    },
  ],

  hard: [
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest electronegativity?",
      options: ["Fluorine", "Oxygen", "Chlorine", "Nitrogen"],
      answer: "Fluorine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the lowest electronegativity?",
      options: ["Francium", "Cesium", "Lithium", "Helium"],
      answer: "Francium",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic number of Uranium?",
      options: ["92", "94", "90", "89"],
      answer: "92",
    },
    {
      question: "Who discovered the electron?",
      options: ["J.J. Thomson", "Rutherford", "Bohr", "Dalton"],
      answer: "J.J. Thomson",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic symbol for Tin?",
      options: ["Sn", "Ti", "Tn", "Ta"],
      answer: "Sn",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic symbol for Antimony?",
      options: ["Am", "Sb", "An", "At"],
      answer: "Sb",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these elements is radioactive?",
      options: ["Uranium", "Carbon", "Bromine", "Sodium"],
      answer: "Uranium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is in period 3, group 16?",
      options: ["Sulfur", "Oxygen", "Selenium", "Tellurium"],
      answer: "Sulfur",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is known as the ‘king of chemicals’?",
      options: ["Sulfuric Acid", "Hydrogen", "Carbon", "Sodium"],
      answer: "Sulfuric Acid",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the symbol of the element discovered by Marie Curie?",
      options: ["Pu", "Ra", "Rn", "Ru"],
      answer: "Ra",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the electron configuration [Ne]3s2 3p4?",
      options: ["Oxygen", "Sulfur", "Selenium", "Tellurium"],
      answer: "Sulfur",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest melting point?",
      options: ["Tungsten", "Carbon", "Osmium", "Iron"],
      answer: "Tungsten",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is a metalloid?",
      options: ["Silicon", "Oxygen", "Magnesium", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Silicon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element forms the diamond structure?",
      options: ["Carbon", "Silicon", "Boron", "Germanium"],
      answer: "Carbon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is used in semiconductors?",
      options: ["Silicon", "Copper", "Iron", "Aluminum"],
      answer: "Silicon",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic number of Chlorine?",
      options: ["16", "17", "18", "19"],
      answer: "17",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is used in nuclear power plants?",
      options: ["Uranium", "Plutonium", "Both A and B", "Thorium"],
      answer: "Both A and B",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is used in thermometers?",
      options: ["Mercury", "Gallium", "Silver", "Zinc"],
      answer: "Mercury",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is essential for bone formation?",
      options: ["Calcium", "Iron", "Sodium", "Potassium"],
      answer: "Calcium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Ni'?",
      options: ["Nickel", "Nitrogen", "Niobium", "Neon"],
      answer: "Nickel",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the heaviest naturally occurring element?",
      options: ["Uranium", "Plutonium", "Radium", "Osmium"],
      answer: "Uranium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is used in disinfectants and bleaches?",
      options: ["Chlorine", "Bromine", "Fluorine", "Iodine"],
      answer: "Chlorine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the symbol 'Pt'?",
      options: ["Platinum", "Palladium", "Protactinium", "Polonium"],
      answer: "Platinum",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is the main component of table salt?",
      options: ["Sodium", "Chlorine", "Both A and B", "Potassium"],
      answer: "Both A and B",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element belongs to group 18?",
      options: ["Neon", "Nitrogen", "Fluorine", "Oxygen"],
      answer: "Neon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is represented by 'Si'?",
      options: ["Silicon", "Silver", "Sulfur", "Sodium"],
      answer: "Silicon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the atomic number 79?",
      options: ["Gold", "Platinum", "Mercury", "Silver"],
      answer: "Gold",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the atomic symbol for Copper?",
      options: ["Cu", "Co", "Cr", "Cp"],
      answer: "Cu",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is found in all organic compounds?",
      options: ["Carbon", "Nitrogen", "Oxygen", "Hydrogen"],
      answer: "Carbon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is responsible for rust formation?",
      options: ["Iron", "Copper", "Zinc", "Lead"],
      answer: "Iron",
    },
  ],

  advanced: [
    {
      question:
        "Which orbital has the highest energy in the ground state of a hydrogen atom?",
      options: ["1s", "2s", "2p", "3s"],
      answer: "3s",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the electron configuration of Sodium?",
      options: [
        "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s1",
        "1s2 2s2 2p5 3s2",
        "1s2 2s2 2p6",
        "1s2 2s1 2p6 3s2",
      ],
      answer: "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s1",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the electron configuration [Ne]3s2 3p5?",
      options: ["Chlorine", "Fluorine", "Bromine", "Oxygen"],
      answer: "Chlorine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest ionization energy?",
      options: ["Helium", "Fluorine", "Neon", "Hydrogen"],
      answer: "Helium",
    },
    {
      question:
        "What is the trend of atomic radius across a period from left to right?",
      options: ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains constant", "Fluctuates"],
      answer: "Decreases",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the trend of ionization energy down a group?",
      options: ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains constant", "Unpredictable"],
      answer: "Decreases",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the lowest electronegativity?",
      options: ["Cesium", "Fluorine", "Helium", "Oxygen"],
      answer: "Cesium",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which element has a completely filled d-subshell in its ground state?",
      options: ["Zinc", "Copper", "Iron", "Chromium"],
      answer: "Zinc",
    },
    {
      question:
        "What type of elements are found on the right side of the periodic table?",
      options: ["Metals", "Nonmetals", "Metalloids", "Transition metals"],
      answer: "Nonmetals",
    },
    {
      question: "Which orbital can hold a maximum of 10 electrons?",
      options: ["s", "p", "d", "f"],
      answer: "d",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which element ends with the electron configuration 4d10 5s2 5p5?",
      options: ["Iodine", "Xenon", "Tellurium", "Antimony"],
      answer: "Iodine",
    },
    {
      question:
        "What is the maximum number of electrons that can occupy the 3p subshell?",
      options: ["2", "6", "10", "14"],
      answer: "6",
    },
    {
      question:
        "What is the periodic trend for metallic character across a period?",
      options: ["Increases", "Decreases", "Stays the same", "Varies randomly"],
      answer: "Decreases",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the largest atomic radius?",
      options: ["Cesium", "Lithium", "Sodium", "Potassium"],
      answer: "Cesium",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which of the following elements has the smallest atomic radius?",
      options: ["Fluorine", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Neon"],
      answer: "Neon",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the configuration [Ar]4s2 3d10 4p5?",
      options: ["Bromine", "Krypton", "Selenium", "Arsenic"],
      answer: "Bromine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest electron affinity?",
      options: ["Fluorine", "Oxygen", "Chlorine", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Chlorine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which group of elements form colored compounds?",
      options: [
        "Alkali metals",
        "Transition metals",
        "Halogens",
        "Noble gases",
      ],
      answer: "Transition metals",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these elements has the highest melting point?",
      options: ["Carbon", "Iron", "Tungsten", "Osmium"],
      answer: "Tungsten",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element forms a +3 ion most easily?",
      options: ["Aluminum", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Calcium"],
      answer: "Aluminum",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the valence configuration ns2 np3?",
      options: ["Nitrogen", "Phosphorus", "Arsenic", "All of these"],
      answer: "All of these",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the oxidation state of sulfur in SO2?",
      options: ["+2", "+4", "+6", "0"],
      answer: "+4",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these elements forms amphoteric oxides?",
      options: ["Zinc", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Sulfur"],
      answer: "Zinc",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element belongs to the actinide series?",
      options: ["Thorium", "Lanthanum", "Hafnium", "Rutherfordium"],
      answer: "Thorium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following has the largest ionization energy?",
      options: ["Neon", "Fluorine", "Argon", "Helium"],
      answer: "Helium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which quantum number determines the shape of an orbital?",
      options: ["Principal (n)", "Azimuthal (l)", "Magnetic (m)", "Spin (s)"],
      answer: "Azimuthal (l)",
    },
    {
      question:
        "How many unpaired electrons are present in oxygen’s ground state?",
      options: ["0", "1", "2", "4"],
      answer: "2",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element violates the octet rule?",
      options: ["Boron", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Neon"],
      answer: "Boron",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the configuration [Kr]5s2 4d10 5p2?",
      options: ["Tin", "Lead", "Germanium", "Silicon"],
      answer: "Tin",
    },
    {
      question:
        "What is the general electron configuration for transition metals?",
      options: [
        "(n-1)d1–10 ns0–2",
        "ns1–2 np1–6",
        "ns2 np6",
        "(n-2)f1–14 (n-1)d0–1 ns2",
      ],
      answer: "(n-1)d1–10 ns0–2",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is most reactive among alkali metals?",
      options: ["Lithium", "Sodium", "Potassium", "Cesium"],
      answer: "Cesium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these elements is paramagnetic?",
      options: ["Oxygen", "Neon", "Helium", "Argon"],
      answer: "Oxygen",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is most likely to gain an electron?",
      options: ["Fluorine", "Chlorine", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen"],
      answer: "Fluorine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which period contains the lanthanides?",
      options: ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
      answer: "6",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which element’s ion has a noble gas configuration after losing one electron?",
      options: ["Sodium", "Calcium", "Potassium", "Magnesium"],
      answer: "Sodium",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which element has the configuration 1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 4s2 3d1?",
      options: ["Scandium", "Titanium", "Vanadium", "Chromium"],
      answer: "Scandium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is NOT a transition metal?",
      options: ["Scandium", "Zinc", "Iron", "Copper"],
      answer: "Zinc",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which of these elements has the lowest first ionization energy?",
      options: ["Cesium", "Rubidium", "Potassium", "Sodium"],
      answer: "Cesium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these elements shows variable oxidation states?",
      options: ["Iron", "Sodium", "Calcium", "Boron"],
      answer: "Iron",
    },
    {
      question: "Which orbital is being filled in lanthanides?",
      options: ["3d", "4d", "4f", "5f"],
      answer: "4f",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the configuration [Xe]4f14 5d10 6s2 6p2?",
      options: ["Lead", "Tin", "Bismuth", "Thallium"],
      answer: "Lead",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these has the smallest second ionization energy?",
      options: ["Sodium", "Magnesium", "Aluminum", "Potassium"],
      answer: "Magnesium",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the effective nuclear charge trend across a period?",
      options: ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains same", "Fluctuates"],
      answer: "Increases",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is isoelectronic with Ne?",
      options: ["Na⁺", "F⁻", "O²⁻", "All of these"],
      answer: "All of these",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element belongs to group 17 and period 4?",
      options: ["Bromine", "Chlorine", "Iodine", "Fluorine"],
      answer: "Bromine",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element is most metallic?",
      options: ["Cesium", "Sodium", "Magnesium", "Aluminum"],
      answer: "Cesium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which quantum number describes the orientation of an orbital?",
      options: ["Principal (n)", "Magnetic (m)", "Azimuthal (l)", "Spin (s)"],
      answer: "Magnetic (m)",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has an f-block electron configuration?",
      options: ["Uranium", "Copper", "Zinc", "Silver"],
      answer: "Uranium",
    },
    {
      question: "Which orbital fills after 6s in the Aufbau principle?",
      options: ["4f", "5d", "6p", "7s"],
      answer: "4f",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which rule states that electrons fill degenerate orbitals singly before pairing?",
      options: [
        "Aufbau’s Principle",
        "Hund’s Rule",
        "Pauli Exclusion Principle",
        "Bohr’s Model",
      ],
      answer: "Hund’s Rule",
    },
    {
      question: "Which element has the highest density?",
      options: ["Osmium", "Tungsten", "Gold", "Iridium"],
      answer: "Osmium",
    },
  ],
};
